Russia is at war with the entire NATO bloc Yes, I do
Россия воюет со всем блоком НАТО Да не
n’t disagree, it can’t lose
не согласен она не может проигрывать вот
just like that to some small Ukraine, you
так просто какой-то маленькой Украине
understand that Ukraine is its size
понимаете что Украина её разма Здра
Hello, hello, I’m from the city of
здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsk You
Хмельницке Вы
[music]
[музыка]
where is Nadym from now Nadym is Magadan
откуда сейчас Надым Надым - это Магадан
Chukotka somewhere there  Yes, in Chukotka, well, in the
Чукотка где-то там да на Чукотке ну й
far north, I understand, but what are you communicating with
крайней севере понял а чём общаетесь
Yamal? Uh-huh Yes,
Ямал Угу
about nothing,
Да ни о чём
Lord, I’m looking at what’s where
Господи так смотрю у что где у
and what are you, I’m looking with the Ukrainian
чего и что вы я смотрю с украинским
flag, probably in the mood for some kind of
флагом наверное настроены на какой-то
political
политический
conversation, yes, maybe I’ll answer your
разговор да давайте может отвечу на Ваши
questions if you have  you have a question,
вопросы если у вас есть вни есть вопрос
you had no desire to move from
у вас не было желания переехать из
Nadym where to
Надыма куда
move from Nadym There was no
из Надыма переехать Не было
desire at all Nadym is considered one of the
желания вообще Надым считается одним из
best cities in
лучших городов
the north, as if no, it wasn’t better, it
севера как бы нет не было вот више да не
wasn’t understood That is, in
было понял То есть в
principle, if we told you, you could
принципе если бы вам скажем можно было
choose  Yeah, so you won the
выбрать Угу что вас вот вы выиграли
lottery And you choose
лотерею И выбираете
one of the listed cities, for example
один из перечисленных городов например
Nadym Paris London and New York And they give you a house there
Надым Париж Лондон и нью-йорк И вам там
and payment for your life for 5 years Well, guys,
и оплату вашей жизни на 5 лет Ну ребятки
you're already on the smoke London New York is
Вы уж на дыму Лондон нью-йорк это совсем
not Russia at all M not  we need this, we
это не Россия М не надо этого мы Россию
love Russia Okay, let's So they give you a
любим Ладно давайте Так вам дают на
choice of Nadym Sochi Moscow and Birobidzhan, what
выбор Надым Сочи Москва и Биробиджан что
would you choose Well, probably Sochi
бы вы выбрали Ну наверное Сочи потому
because Moscow is a more populated city in the
что Москва более такой населённый город
people of
нар
Sochi And what is now stopping you from leaving
Сочи А что вам сейчас мешает свалить из
Nadym
Надыма
Well, nothing is stopping you, everything is
Ну ничего не мешает всё
fine Well, you said  there to choose And I'm there
хорошо Ну вы сказали там выбрать А я там
Sochi Sochi we visit
Сочи Сочи мы там посещаем
Sochi there is good And what are the advantages of living in
Сочи хорошо А какие какие плюсы жизни в
Nadym? You can
Надыме можете
say the advantages of
сказать плюсы
ecology
экология
that
что
ecology I correctly understand that the smoke
экология я правильно понимаю что на дым
was made as a city for some kind of
делался как город под какое-то
production for some kind of production and you
производство по какую-то добычу и вы
say that this is good
говорите что это хоро
Yes, why is there a good environment in
Да а чем хорошая экология в
Nadym? Well, in our city there is only one
Надыме Ну у нас в городе только одна
pipe that heats the city; there are no more
труба которая отапливает город больше
pipes
труб
at all;
нету никаких вообще
you won’t
никаких не
believe it. Well, that is, you
поверите Ну то есть у вас
only have a centralized boiler room. Yes, there is only one
централизованная котельня только Да одна
boiler room and there is nothing else. I don’t understand, there are no
котельна и всё больше ничего нет Поня ни
factories, nothing else, everything
заводов ничего остальное всё
is there  if anyone is looking for an
там есть если кто кто ищет там
environmentally friendly place like Greta
экологически чистое место типа там Грета
Thunberg there, then they can go to the smoke Yes, well,
тунберг то может ехать на дым Да ну у
we have a little low pressure here Yes Well,
нас немножко низкое давление тут Да Ну
well, who cares
это ну кому как
Yeah, low pressure and low
Угу низкое давление и низкие
temperatures Yes, it’s still winter here,
температуры Да у нас до сих пор зима
I can show you the street before us  these
могу показать улицу нас ещё до сих
Show it’s interesting Let’s see I’m
Покажите интересно Давайте вот Я вот
sitting in the kitchen right now, look at the kindergarten
сейчас на кухне сижу смотрите вот садик
Yes, there’s still snow and
Да вот снег ещё а
I’m wearing a shirt
я вон в рубашечка хожу
like you have snow
типа у вас снег
Yes, my shirt is so light too and
Да меня тоже рубашечка такая лёгкая а
this is on your smoke right now White nights, yes
это у вас на дыме сейчас Белые ночи да
it turns out Well, it’s
получается Ну
night all night  Well, almost no, it
да ночь кругло ночь Ну почти нет она в
will be cool in June, I’ll tell you what
июне будет кру вот у вас сейчас сколько
time it is
время
now, but I see the clock, I
сейчас скажу А вот часы я вижу я сзади
see the clock behind you
вижу часы вас
0248, yes, that is, you succeed and it’s
0248 да то есть у вас получается и у вас
light at night, yes
светло ночью да
Well, not quite yet in June there will be the
Ну не совсем ещё в июне будет самая
fullest night Well  for a full day,
полная ночь Ну по полный день
or rather, I
вернее
understood it’s
понял
interesting, well, no, why are you
интересно ну что ж Нет а что вы так с
sitting upright with a flag, you’re drowning for Ukraine like that,
флагом сидите прямо вы так за Украину
yes,
топите да
I’m actually from Czechoslovakia myself, I’m
Я вообще из Чехословакии сам Я
Czechoslovakian, my grandmother comes from
чехословаки у меня бабушка родом из
Ukraine, it’s just that I support
Украины просто и я поддерживаю
Ukraine,
Украину
and what good do you think about Ukraine?  I’ve
и что в Украине хорошего вы думаете я не
never lived in
жил никогда в
Ukraine, why did you hang up the flag because
Украине а зачем вы флаг повесили потому
I support Ukraine from the Russian
что я поддерживаю Украину от российского
aggressor, we’re collecting here in Czechoslovakia.
агрессора мы тут в Чехословакии собираем
I’m just a Czechoslovakian blogger. Yes, and I’m in
Я просто блогер чехословацкий Да и я в
Czechoslovakia, collecting donations from various
Чехословакии собирая вот с разных чих
Slovaks, we’re collecting donations for the
словаков мы донаты собираем на
Armed Forces of Ukraine for
Вооружённые силы Украины на
denazification, I’ll
денацификация
tell you what  you are doing everything in vain, I don’t
вам скажу что вы напрасно всё делаете не
know Well, here we are like Samurai, here the main
знаю Ну тут мы как Самураи тут главное
way Well, as you
путь Ну как бы
know, a nail against a sledgehammer, as it were,
знаешь гвоздь против кувалды как бы так
And you are for a nail, yes Why look,
это А вы за гвоздя да Почему смотри
a nail against a sledgehammer is very good if the
гвоздь против кувалда очень хорошо если
sledgehammer hits Yes, but the nail is shorter Go in the
кувалда лупит Да а гвоздь короче Гоп в
hand and that’s
руку и всё
it  in any case, yes, it will bend, no, the
и в любом случае сть загнется нет
sledgehammer can hit the owner in the leg
кувалда может хозяину по ноге дать
in short and he will be the point is that you
короче и он будет дело в том что вы же
understand, look, Ukraine Well, if
понимаете смотрите Украина Ну если бы
Ukraine itself was at war with Russia, I think
Украина сама воевала с Россией Я думаю
2-3 days and Kiev would be taken, but you
2-3 дня и Киев бы взяли но вы же
understand that Ukraine is  everything grew
понимаете что Украина ются всё рос
Russia is at war with the entire NATO bloc You
Россия воюет со всем блоком НАТО Вы же
agree We Czechoslovakia is also in the
согласны Мы Чехословакия тоже в блоке
NATO bloc No no I disagree Russia is at war with the
НАТО Нет нет не согласен Россия воюет со
entire NATO bloc Yes I don’t disagree, she
всем блокам НАТО Да не не согласен она
can’t lose just like that to
не может проигрывать вот так просто
some small Ukraine You understand that
какой-то маленькой Украине понимаете что
Ukraine of its size is not at war  I understand that
Украина её разма не воюет Я понимаю что
it’s a shame to admit, but you are at war with the entire
это стыдно признать но вы воюете со всем
NATO bloc, admit with the entire NATO bloc, the
блоком НАТО признать со всем блоком НАТО
entire NATO bloc has its own industry,
Весь блок НАТО свои промышленность
military instructors, it’s a shame to admit that the NATO
инструктора военны это стыдно признать
bloc is
бло НАТО сри ско блок НАТО
losing, it’s losing, it’s losing, no,
проигрывает получается проигрывает Да не
why is it losing, look, the
Почему проигрывает смотрите блок
NATO bloc is taking out Gazprom here.  you have
НАТО выносит вот у вас Газпром вот у вас
Gazprom in Nadym right Well, of course,
в Надыме ш Газпром правильно Ну конечно
yes, you saw this news. Yes, Gazprom
да вы видели эту новость Да что Газпром
reported. That last year, for
отчитался Что за прошлый год у него
the first time since ninety-nine, he
впервые с девяносто девятого года ничего
saw nothing. Well, no, he doesn’t have a profit,
не видел Вот есть нет у него не прибыль
but a loss, a loss, that
а убыток убыток то
is, a duck
есть утка
Well, yours Once again, yours  Gazprom I’ll
Ну ваш Ещё раз Ваш Газпром Я вот сейчас
read it directly to you now, not to us, but your
вам прям зачитаю не нам говорят А ваш
Gazprom is telling you, the comrades of
Газпром говорит вам товарищи
the station there are telling you. Now I’ll read it to you directly
станци там говорят Сейчас я тебе прямо
so that you
прочитаю чтобы ты своими
can see with your own ears,
ушами узрел
so now, and
так сейчас
so Gazprom at the end of 2023 went into
вот Газпром по итогам 2023 года ушёл в
a loss, it amounted to 629 billion rubles, it follows
убыток он составил 629 млрд руб следует
from its  report on international standards and a link to
из его отчёта по междуна и ссылка на
this report to international standards
этот отчёт международным стандартам
a year earlier, the company had a profit of 1.2
годом ранее у компании была прибыль 1,2
trillion
триллион
rubles Well, so what, for the first time since
рублей Ну и что ничего впервые за с
1999, Gazprom suffered
девяносто девятого года Газпром потерпел
losses, well, well, and you’ll be sucking your
убытки вот ну и ну и и будете сосать
paw soon
лапу скоро
anyway. I don’t know, I, I  I don’t feel it
вообще Я не знаю я я не чувствую этого
Well, that’s right, you don’t feel it, yes, in a
Ну правильно не чувствуешь да Через
month you will feel it in two or three
месяц почувствуешь через два через три
how should I feel tell me how to
как мне чувствовать скажи мне как
feel what I should You do nothing You
чувствовать что я должен Ты ничего Ты
look you feel the low pressure and
смотри ты чувствуй низкое давление и
low temperature nothing depends on you
низкую температуру от тебя же ничего не
really You
зависит правда Ты же ничего ты же не
can’t do anything  influence nothing Well, what will you
можешь повлиять ни на что Ну а что ты
do if you feel So what will you
сделаешь вот если ты почувствуешь Так ты
come out and say Putin in short Put
что выйдешь и скажешь Путин короче Верни
everything back as it was of course you won’t be able to say
Всё как было конечно не сможешь сказать
you don’t have enough spirit I understand Putin is
у тебя духа не хватит Я понимаю Путин
handsome I understand Yes what can you do All you
красавчик я понимаю Да что тебе
have to do is say Putin is handsome
Останется только сказать Путин красавчик
otherwise you  on the bottle from No, wait
иначе тебя на бутыля от Нет подожди
differently, I and you are behind the collapse of the bodies You are
по-другому я а ты ж за крх тел Ты же
closed the bodies, it’s
закр тел
true Putin is really handsome I’m the ones
правда Путин реально красавчик я те гор
in what he’s handsome in, yes, we’ve
в чём в чём он красавчик да мы тут
healed here, we’re building everything, we’re smoking, everything is
зажили у нас всё строится мы дыми всё
being built, salaries are
строится зарплаты
growing seriously
растут серьёзно
of course And how much  your salary How much is
конечно А сколько у вас зарплата Сколько
my salary Well, how much do you think
у меня зарплата Ну как думаешь сколько у
my
меня
salary is salary in Nadym I think 2000
зарплата зарплата в Надыме Я думаю 2000
dollars for
долларов у
you Well, you're right 200,000 rubles yes and yes
вас Ну ты прав 200.000 руб да и да
great This is it Well this is stimulation for the fact that
пра Это ж это Это ж стимуляция за то что
people live in these terrible conditions
люди живут вот этих ужасных условиях
cold hunger
холод голод
I  I live normally, these conditions are what we
я нормально живу се условия какой у нас
have Catch the code, tell me if you want to
возьми Поймай кода скажи захочешь
move How did you guess so And why did you
пересели Как так отгадал А почему ты так
say that, smart, smart man, I
сл сказал-то умны умный человек я я же
understand that look, if it’s like that in Russia, damn
понимаю что смотрите если так в России
it’s a small salary, but in Nadym they
блин маленькая зарплата да то в Надыме
should have at least a little bit of it
хоть чуть-чуть её должны
increase How much do you think a
повысить Как думаешь сколько у нас
teacher in
зарабатывает учитель в
Nadym earns? Yes, 100,000 rubles, 1,000 dollars
Надыме Да 100.000 руб 1000 долларов
exactly. How do you know that? Look,
точно Откуда ты тако знаешь смотри
because he can’t
потому потому что он не может
earn more there than you, gas, or
зарабатывать там больше чем ты газок или
whoever you are, that is, most likely his
кто ты там да то есть скорее всего его
half, that’s
половине вот и
all, he answered clearly Yes  that’s exactly what it is, that’s
всё ответил чётко Да точно так и есть
all, that’s why Well, the prices are the same
вот и всё поэтому Ну а цены те же самые
Why is it cold We travel, we go wherever we
Почему холоде Мы путешествуем ездим куда
want good question, what do you think people
хочем хорошо вопрос как ты думаешь люди
from Moscow are moving to
из Москвы переезжают в
Nadym
Надым
Yes seriously
Да серьёзно
Yes Especially because teachers
Да Особенно потому что учителя здесь
earn money here That’s what you said very
зарабатывают Вот как ты сказал очень
well that is  teachers Come for
хорошо то есть учителя Приезжают на
permanent residence in
постоянное место жительства в
Nadym and it’s an environmentally friendly city, in short,
Надым да экологически чистый короче
it’s the Northern one, look,
город самый такой вот Северный посмотри
here’s one of the best cities you can
вот один из лучших городов можешь
see, fly one of the best cities
посмотреть лети один из лучших городов
Where in Russia,
Где в России
well, the North in the north is
ну Севе на севере
not the North, not the North, I understand Russia,
не Север не Север я понимаешь России это
you can see you know what  in Russia
ты можешь увидеть знаешь чего в России
you look
ты посмотришь
closer to the south there yes There it is well Crimea there
ближе к югу туда да Там это ну Крым там
here
сюда
Yes these are the best cities in the north I
Да это лучшие города на севере Я имею в
mean so in the north Well why do people live
виду так на севере Ну зачем людям жить
in the north That is, no one goes there
на севере То есть туда же никто не едет
Listen
Слушай
ecology ecology is just
экология экология просто
tough Yes there is ecology in general  I'm telling you,
жесть Да тут вообще экология я те говорю
one pipe is burning more and more, nothing
одна труба горит всё больше ничего
more, how much life expectancy do you have in
сколько у вас продолжительность жизни в
Nadym
Надыме
Wednesday? That's what I won't tell you, ecology.
сред Вот этого я не скажу тебе экология
You probably have people living for up to 100
У вас наверно должны люди жить под 100
years, no, not 100 years. Well, usually I don't know
лет не ну не 100 лет Ну обычно не знаю
everything is fine there. In this regard, I  I
там всё хорошо В этом плане на я вот это
won’t tell you this, I’m not not a
вот не скажу тебе я же тебе не не
sociologist, so you’re asking me such things,
социолог так спрашиваешь мне такие вещи
you have
у вас
ecology pressure Yes, lower Yes, but the
экология давление Да пониже Да а
ecology is good pressure, lower
экология хорошая давление пониженная
ecology is good
экология хорошая
Yes,
Да
yes, it’s cool, the
да прикольно
best city in the north I’m
лучший город севера Я за свой город
holding my fist very tightly for my city, I’m keeping my fist
очень сильно кулачок держу кулачок как
tight.
плотно держи кулачок
very
очень
tight It’s cool, and you have some kind of
плотно Прикольно а у вас есть какая-то
football
футбольная
team Listen, there are probably children’s
команда Слушай наверное есть детские
youth clubs that are like, well, a small town
юношеские такие ну ну маленький город
that 40,000 people there,
что 40.000 человек там
they want small there are among themselves
хоче маленький есть меж собой
playing Where Where Where children go after
играют Куда Куда Куда дети уезжают после
studying at school in Tyumen in Tyumen
обучения в школе в Тюмень в Тюмень
they leave Tyumen Tyumen in St. Petersburg  they are leaving, that is, they do
уезжают Тюмень Тюмень в Питер уезжают то
n’t want to stay in the smoke. No, of course they don’t, why is it such the best city, this is the best city in the North, and they don’t want to stay? Well, it’s not the best city on earth, you know. That’s what’s wrong. I think that Nadym is fair. I don’t want your city.  behind which you are holding
не хочу твой город за которой ты держишь
the onion,
лучок
uh, somehow offend, but it seems to me that this is
ээ как-то обидеть но мне кажется что это
the ass of
вот [__]
the world, this is the ass of the world, this is the best ass in the world,
мира это [__] мира это лучшая [__]
so you can sum it up for me,
мира можешь так вот мне под резюмировать
tell Nadym - this is the best ass in the world, this is the
скажи Надым - это лучшая [__] мира это
best ass in the world, an absolutely cool
лучшая [__] мира абсолютно классный
city,
город
in general, we have a beauty contest  this is a
вообще нас есть конкурс красоты это
competition of the world’s [ __ ], don’t you understand that this is a
конкурс жоп мира не понимаешь что это
very populous city,
очень многочисленный город
uh, in the north In fact, there is
ээ на севере На самом деле есть
more or less Well, there is, let’s say sugar
более-менее Ну есть вот допустим сахар
He And what kind of car do you have?
Он А какая у тебя
car I don’t have a car I’m not a
машина машина у меня нет машины я не
driver Why don’t you have
водитель А почему у тебя нет
a car I’m not a driver I  I don’t know how to drive a
машины я не водитель Я не умею водить
car, I’ve never passed my license. Why
машину не сдавал на права никогда А что
can’t you
не можешь
pass it? Why do I need it?
сдать А зачем мне её
We have a small town, we have nowhere to go there,
у нас маленький город у нас там ездить
well, of course, we have a lot of
некуда ну у нас есть конечно там много
cars, there’s a row of cars here. Do you want me to show you?
машин вон тут ряд машин Хочешь покажу А
Why do people need it? Yes, yes, I’m with  windows I saw
зачем людям Да вот да я же с окна видел
people have cars there Why do they need cars, why do they have
там у людей машины Зачем им машины зачем
two of them, everything is delivered by cars Why do they need
две те всё доставлено машинами так Зачем
cars And you don’t
им машины А вам не
need me, don’t drive cars in
нужно я не езди на машинах во
You
У вас
have Yes, of course I
есть Есть конечно
understand they are in cars, they have a car and
Понял они на машинах у них есть машина а
I don’t
мне не
need a letter to my Telegram  right now
нужна пись на мий Telegram прям зараз
axis vin
ось вин
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
driving us through the skargi ODS into your ban
загоняя нас через скарги ОРВ в твый бан
and even more videos you don’t show people
и дуже багато видео не показуе людям
at all times you don’t show information about streams for
вчасно не показуе информация про стримы
this purpose for that in Mali operational
тому для того щоб ми Мали оперативный
link to write directly at once and while there in
звязок пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в
telegra okrim video  ezh tezh Tsikava and
телегра окрим видео ще теж цикава и
Korisna information and we are sorry for you
корисна информация и ми повинни з вами
trimati postiyny operational link
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава Украине пись